SAHIL GUPTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - CLOUD

CLOUD ENGINEER AND DEVOPS ROLES





PHONE EMAIL LINKEDIN GITHUB

+91-8087978438 <u>sahilg9810@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/sahilgupta2810</u> <u>SahilGupta2810</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in GIT, Docker, developing CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, Automation, Scripting and worked on AWS services like AWS Lambda, API Gateway, ECS, Load Balancer, VPC, and EC2. while managing it through Infrastructure as Code.

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate

March 06, 2023 Verify **AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner**

September 05, 2021

Verify

SKILLS

AWS Lambda, SNS, SQS, API Gateway, IAM, CloudFormation, S3, EC2, CloudFront, CloudWatch, LoadBalancer, ECS, EKS

Docker

Node.js

Infrastructure as Code - Terraform, CloudFormation, CDK

Linux, Windows

✓ CI/CD tools [GitHub Actions , Jenkins]

Scripting [Bash]

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TCS - Software Engineer

30 September, 2022 - Present

[Transition through WM Universal Solution Pvt Ltd]

WM Universal Solution Pvt. Ltd. - 14 March, 2022 - 29 September, 2022

- Built, deployed, and operated infrastructure and applications on AWS for applications, including AWS Lambda, API Gateway, ECS, Load Balancer, VPC, EC2, ECR, EKS, DynamoDB.
- Utilized **Terraform**, **CloudFormation** and **CDK** to define and provision infrastructure as code, streamlining deployment processes and reducing manual configuration errors.
- Implemented release management practices using **Jenkins**, ensuring smooth and efficient deployment of software updates.
- Implemented, designed, and deployed **Docker** and **Kubernetes** solutions to streamline application deployment and improve scalability.
- Utilized monitoring tools such as Grafana and Cloudwatch to proactively identify and resolve system issues.
- Collaborated with development team to identify and implement best practices for infrastructure automation, testing, and deployment.

Kyndryl - Associate Technical Engineer

29 April, 2021 - 08 March, 2022

- Conducted capacity planning, performance management, application monitoring, and health checks for multiple applications.
- Created project reports and followed user creation policies to manage users and groups.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Cloud Resume Challenge

GitHub Blog

17 December, 2022 - 25 January , 2022

 Deployed a static website along with a visitor counter using AWS S3, Lambda, DynamoDB, API Gateway and utilized CloudFront, Route 53, ACM, DNS management, SSL/TLS certificate, and CI/CD using GitHub Action respectively.

URL Shortner

GitHub

04 December, 2022 - 10 December, 2022

- Services Used: API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB
- Build an Rest API that takes an long URL as an input along with shorter name and stores it in DynamoDB.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2020 | VIIT, Pune

BE

Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering

2014 - 2017 | Government Polytechnic

Diploma

Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering

SSC Mahara

Maharashtra Board

2004 - 2014 | DHS

PUBLICATIONS

Medium